

John Bedeir DevOps Engineer

+20 109 699 3853

john.bedeir@gmail.com

www.johnydev.com

Copenhagen, Denmark

SUMMARY

I am a skilled DevOps Engineer with 2+ years of hands-on experience and total 10 years of experience, an expert in Windows OS, Linux & Unix, with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevOps culture, currently I am focusing on applying Build, Test, maintain the infrastructure to speed up the development and release process using CI /CD and Cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a Sr. System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management.

Then I became an IT Manager, which was more managerial level than technical, starting with Identify the need for upgrades, configurations or new systems and report to the MD, assign tasks, monitor project pipeline, managing servers, during this time I was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer 01/2020 - Present

Orange Business Services (Cairo, Egypt)

- Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
- Working in Software development life cycle
- Working in AGILE & Concept of Infrastructure as a Code.
- · Participating in Front-End Development.
- Integrate Maven, Tomcat, Gitlab with Jenkins
- Project-1: Using Docker to containerize a web app
- Project-2: Build CI/CD automation with GitLab for web app
- Project-3: Manage all build and deploy tools, and oversee all-deployments using Kubernetes, Ansible & Jenkins
- Project-4: Working with AWS using (EC2, IAM, Security groups, ect.)
- Project-5: Django app & environment setup, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins, AWS Deployment
- Project-6: PHP, Laravel environment setup, integrating Jenkins with Gitlab CI/CD, AWS Deployment.
- Project-7: Integrating Jenkins and Maven with Gitlab, setup Tomcat Server and use Docker, Ansible & Kubernetes in CI/CD Pipeline.
- Project-8: Setting up Kubernetes Cluster, EC2, Route53, S3 Bucket and IAM on AWS with Deploy and Service using Terraform & Ansible

IT Manager 09/2018 - 09/2019

Yaryor Technologies (Dubai, UAE)

- Managing 5 employees
- · Monitor performance of information technology systems to determine cost and productivity levels
- · Handle annual budget and ensure cost effectiveness
- · Creating scripts to automate tasks

Senior System Administrator

ridssoo bo (ooria, bargaria)

03/2016 - 04/2018

- Plus 500 BG (Sofia, Bulgaria)
- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- · Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.

- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned.

Senior System Administrator

Aroma Studios (Cairo, Egypt)

- Level 1 2 Support for all instance (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure Linux / Unix and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure assigned & pending tasks have been solved.
- Ensure there are no alerts in Kaspersky endpoint security management console.
- Check the Servers & Render-farm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

System Administrator

09/2011 - 12/2013

01/2014 - 07/2015

Arabcomed (Cairo, Egypt)

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Software & Hardware Troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

Computer Science and Engineering

2019

Technical University (Sofia, Bulgaria) - Masters Degree

Computer Science 2011

Future Academy (Cairo, Egypt) - Bachelor's Degree

SKILLS

Linux / Unix	Expert	MCSA	Expert
Windows OS	Expert	Kubernetes	Advanced
Docker	Expert	Ansible	Advanced
Bash Scripting	Expert	Vagrant	Advanced
VMware, Parallels, Virtualbox	Expert	RHCSA / RHCSE	Advanced
Git, Github, Gitlab & Bitbucket	Expert	AWS	Intermediate
Web Hosting	Expert	Terraform	Intermediate
WAMP, XAMPP	Expert	Jenkins	Intermediate
Apache, Nginx	Expert	Python	Intermediate
HTML5 / CSS3	Expert	REST API, SOAP, OpenCV	Intermediate
SSH & Putty	Expert	JavaScript	Intermediate

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native Bulgarian Basic

English Fluent